<data:item xmlns:data="data" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="data ../../xsd/eb-hub.xsd" id="nxp_om13790_host" name="OM13790 Host" type="arduino_header" vendor="nxp">
  <images>
    <file path="nxp_OM13790_Host.png"/>
  </images>
  <display_title>USB Type-C Shield Board Gen 2 with Display Port Alt Mode</display_title>
  <overview>The host board is a video source device over USB Type-C. It supports power source during power up default. Runtime configuration for power role swap and data role swap.

NXP’s Generation 2.0 USB Type-C shield board, combined with an MCUXpresso SDK with USB Power Delivery Stack, allows you to tether a USB Type-C connector to select Kinetis®, LPC, and i.MX RT Development Platforms. This shortens the learning curve by leveraging NXP’s Easy-to-use hardware and MCUXpresso software and tools, the only solution like it on the market. It enables Type-C support for display port alt-mode with seamless effort and offers numerous voltage protection services, promising easy and effective designs.

Jump into development quickly with our ready-to-play USB Type-C Development Kit, including the USB Type-C Shield Generation 2 host or dock board, an AC/DC Adapter to power the shield board, MCUXpresso SDK with USB Power Delivery Stack, and hardware and software setup guides. Get the USB Type-C full development kit and experience it for yourselves.
Fact sheet: https://www.nxp.com/docs/en/fact-sheet/GEN2SHIELDBRDFS.pdf</overview>
  <category name="interface">
    <category name="usb"/>
  </category>
  <links>
    <link type="product" href="https://www.nxp.com/products/interfaces/usb-interfaces/usb-type-c/om13790-host-dock-usb-type-c-shield-board-gen-2-with-display-port-alt-mode:OM13790"/>
    <link type="sdk" href="https://mcuxpresso.nxp.com/criteria/8a9583ce23bb"/>
  </links>
  <nxp_compatible_hw>
    <hw id="FRDM-K22F"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso54018"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso54114"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso55S16"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso55S28"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso55S36"/>
    <hw id="LPCXpresso55S69"/>
    <hw id="MC56F83000-EVK"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT1015"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT1020"/>
    <hw id="MIMXRT1060-EVKB"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT1060"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT1064"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT595"/>
    <hw id="EVK-MIMXRT685"/>
    <hw id="MIMXRT685-AUD-EVK"/>
    <hw id="EVKB-IMXRT1050"/>
    <hw id="MIMXRT1024-EVK"/>
    <hw id="MIMXRT1170-EVK"/>
  </nxp_compatible_hw>
</data:item>